bookingbug.com 2019-03-22

# Privacy Policy - BookingBug

We are committed to protecting your personal information and being transparent about the data we hold about you **("personal data")**

This privacy policy, together with our [Cookies Policy](https://www.bookingbug.com/cookies) applies to all visitors and users of our websites at https://www.bookingbug.com and https://www.bookingbug.co.uk (the "sites") and our online services and sets out how we will use your personal data as well as your privacy rights. It also relates to personal data you provide to us by phone, SMS, email, in letters and other correspondence and in person.

This privacy policy does not apply to the processing of personal data made available by our customers and their end users via our booking services (including booking services subscribed for by you via our sites). Such processing is governed by the terms of the applicable booking services contract between us and the customer.

We use your information in line with all applicable laws and regulations concerning the protection of personal data from time to time in force, including the Data Protection Act 2018, the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 and 2011 and the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR), and including any amendments or updates to these and any equivalent or successor applicable laws and regulations. Nothing in this privacy policy shall limit your statutory rights in relation to your personal data.

### 1\. WHO WILL HOLD YOUR INFORMATION?

For the purposes of this privacy policy, the data controller is BookingBug Limited ("BookingBug" or "we"). We are registered in England and Wales under number 6770610. Our registered office address is 150 Wharfedale Road, Winnersh Triangle, Berkshire, England, RG41 5RB. Our VAT number is GB 9461839 91.

### 2\. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW?

2.1. We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal data:

  * **Identity Data:** name, title, username or other identifier, title;
  * **Contact Data:** billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers;
  * **Transaction Data:** details about payments to and from you and other details of services you have purchased from us;
  * **Technical Data:** internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and other technology on the devices you use to access this website;
  * **Profile Data:** your username and password, subscriptions made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses;
  * **Usage Data:** information about how you use our sites and services;
  * **Marketing and Communications Data:** your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences; and
  * **Other:** any other information you chose to send or otherwise make available to us.

2.2. We use different methods to collect personal data from and about you as follows:

Direct Interactions: You may give us your personal data directly by filling in forms on our sites or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:

  * create an account on our sites;
  * subscribe to our booking services;
  * use our LIVE HELP chat function;
  * subscribe to our newsletter and other publications;
  * request marketing to be sent to you;
  * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
  * give us feedback, report a problem with our sites or otherwise contact us.

Automated Technologies or interactions: As you interact with our sites, we will automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.bookingbug.com/cookies) for further details.

Third parties or publicly available sources: We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below:

  * Technical Data, for example from: 
    * analytics providers such as Google;
    * advertising networks; and
    * search information providers.
  * Contact, Financial and Transaction Data from providers of technical and payment services such as our third party card payment service providers.
  * Identity and Contact Data from publicly available sources such as Companies House.

2.3. We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

2.4. We may keep a record of correspondence, telephone calls or online live chat communications if you contact us.

2.5. We may monitor or record your communications with us to assist us with the development of our sites and services; to train our staff; and if so requested by order of a court, regulatory body or law enforcement organisation.

### 3\. HOW DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

3.1. We will only use your personal data for the purposes specified in this privacy policy or in relevant parts of the sites and only ever as permitted by law.

3.2. We may use your personal information to:

  * verify your identity;
  * manage our relationship with you for example registering your account; notifying you about changes to our privacy policy, asking you to leave a review or take a survey;
  * provide and administer the sites and our related services and manage internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes, and to develop the sites and our services to improve your experience;
  * perform a contract we may have with you including to provide booking services you have subscribed for, to manage payment, fees and charges and collect and recover money owed to us;
  * send you general (non-marketing) commercial communications including relating to booking services you have subscribed for from us;
  * send you email notifications which you have specifically requested;
  * send you our newsletter and other marketing communications relating to our business or the businesses of carefully-selected third parties which we think may be of interest to you by post or, where you have specifically agreed to this, by email or similar technology; and
  * deal with enquiries and complaints made by you;

If you subscribe for our services including our booking services online you may be required to provide payment card details. We use third party payment card providers to manage all of our online card transactions. We ourselves do not retain any record of your payment card information. You should only provide your personal data to those payment card providers after reviewing their privacy policies, which are available on their website(s). Your payment card information is used solely to process payments you make via our sites or for fraud prevention and detection purposes. All of our payment card providers collect payment card information via a secure online payment gateway.

### 4\. MARKETING AND CONSENT

4.1. We may use your personal data to form a view on what products, services and offers may be of interest to you ("marketing").

4.2. You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased services from us and you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

4.3. We will always obtain your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party for marketing purposes.

4.4. You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you at any time or here at <http://go.bookingbug.com/UnsubscribePage.html>.

### 5\. LAWFUL BASIS FOR USING YOUR PERSONAL DATA

5.1. We process your personal data based on the lawful bases set out below. We may process information you provide based on more than one lawful basis depending on the specific purpose for which we are using it.

  * **Contract:** To enter into a contract with you and fulfil our contractual obligations to you (e.g. to provide you with booking services which you subscribe for). This processing is necessary for us to provide the service you have requested including registering and managing your account with us and providing service updates and related information).
  * **Consent:** Where you have consented to our use of your personal data, for example where you opt-in toinfose receive relevant marketing communications from us (e.g. industry news and offers)
  * **Legal Obligation:** Where processing is necessary to comply with legal or statutory requirements on us. This may include cooperating with police in relation to their investigations.
  * **Legitimate interest:** Where processing is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) provided that these do not conflict with your interests or fundamental rights. This may include, to improve our sites and services, understand how visitors and customers use our sites and services, undertake market research and inform our marketing, to run our business and maintain the security of our sites and services for you, us and other sites visitors and customers.

### 6\. DISCLOSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA

6.1. Except as provided in this privacy policy, we will not provide your information to third parties.

6.2. We may disclose your personal data to any of our employees, officers, agents, suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes as set out in this privacy policy.

6.3. We may disclose your personal data to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006 ("Group Companies").

6.4. We may also use or disclose your personal data as follows:

  * to provide third parties with statistical information about our users but this information will not be used to identify you personally; and
  * to third party service providers who may from time to time support our sites and services including our third party Live Help Chat provider.

6.5. In addition, we may disclose your personal data:

  * to the extent that we are required to do so by law, or in connection with any legal proceedings or
  * to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purpose of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk); and
  * in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, to the prospective buyer or seller of such business and assets and their advisers. If our business is sold your details will be passed onto the new owner of the business.

6.6. We may share any information that we collect with parties including: our legal and professional advisors, the police, other public or private sector agencies, governmental or representative bodies (which Manyinclude insurance companies, finance companies and/or other agencies) in accordance with the relevant legislation for the purposes of the prevention or detection of offences, and/or the apprehension organisationprosecution of offenders

### 7\. STORING AND TRANSFERRING YOUR DATA

7.1. We share your personal data with our Group Companies. This will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

7.2. Many of our external third parties are based outside the EEA so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

7.3. Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * Your personal data is transferred to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details see: https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en
  * In relation to certain service providers, by using specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between Europe and the US. For further details, see https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

### 8\. SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

8.1. Data transmission over the Internet is inherently insecure and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the Internet.

8.2. We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

8.3. We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

8.4. You are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. We will not ask you for your password.

### 9\. RETENTION PERIOD

9.1. We will process personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purpose we collected it for, including the purpose of legal, accounting and reporting requirements, and for as long as necessary for the prevention and detection of criminal activity. The period for which we process and store the personal data for varies depending on the use you make of the sites and services we offer. Where you register an account or subscribe for our services we will retain your personal data for as long as your account is live or as necessary to continue to provide you with our services and for a further period thereafter to enable us to satisfy our legal, accounting and reporting requirements.

9.2. In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Right to be forgotten below for further information.

9.3. In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice.

### 10\. YOUR RIGHTS

10.1. At any point while we are in possession of or processing your personal data, you, the data subject, have the following rights:

  * Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. In the event that we refuse your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why;
  * Right of rectification – you have a right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete;
  * Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records;
  * Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply to have a right to restrict the processing;
  * Right of portability – in certain circumstances you have the right to have the data we hold about you transferred to another organisation;
  * Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing, automated processing or profiling; and
  * Right to complain to the supervisory authority – you have the right to complain as outlined in section 14 below

Please email infosec@bookingbug.com if you have any queries regarding your rights. You can exercise your rights as set out above by emailing infosec@bookingbug.com and/or by following Manage Your Data Preferences [here](http://go.bookingbug.com/data-preferences.html). All of the above requests will be forwarded on should there be a third party involved (as set out in this Privacy Policy) in the processing of your personal data.

### 11\. UPDATING INFORMATION

11.1. Please let us know if the personal information which we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated.

### 12\. POLICY AMENDMENTS

12.1. We may update this privacy policy from time-to-time by posting a new version on our sites. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes.

12.2. We may also notify you of changes to our privacy policy by email.

### 13\. THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

13.1. The sites may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit

### 14\. CONTACT AND COMPLAINTS

14.1. If you wish to make a complaint about how your personal data is being processed by BookingBug (or third parties as described above), or how your complaint has been handled, in the first instance please email your concerns to [infosec@bookingbug.com](mailto:infosec@bookingbug.com). You also have the right to lodge a complaint directly with the UK supervisory authority which is the Information Commissioner’s Office and can be contacted via the details at www.ico.org.uk.

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our treatment of your personal data, please  
Email [infosec@bookingbug.com](mailto:infosec@bookingbug.com)

OR

Post to  
BookingBug Ltd  
2nd floor, 3-7 Herbal Hill  
EC1R 5EJ, London  
United Kingdom
